<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Darius Foo</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Darius Foo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Darius Foo.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 14:17:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dariusf.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jump-to-definition in PL papers</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/latex-notation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 14:17:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/latex-notation/</guid><description>PL papers tend to use lots of notation. To manage this, paper sources usually include a &amp;quot;macros.tex&amp;quot; containing a slew of \newcommands, defining wonderful languages of terms and naming all the clever judgments and syntactic sugar.
While notation can increase clarity, it can cause difficulty to readers, who haven't had the hundreds of hours of practice the authors have had using and reading those intricate strings of symbols, and internalizing their precedences and meaning.</description></item><item><title>Ordering events across live loops in Sonic Pi</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/sonic-pi-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:50:17 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/sonic-pi-time/</guid><description>Sonic Pi has an elegant and well-thought temporal semantics. Using the following program as an example,
sample :drum_bass_hard play :c sleep 1 sample :drum_cowbell The drum sample and note can be thought of as starting simultaneously, and the cowbell will play precisely one second1 after. In other words, sleep there isn't actually POSIX's sleep - it can be thought of as delimiting a section on a virtual timeline, a section which does not include the time taken to start playing the sample and note.</description></item><item><title>Trees with holes</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/trees-with-holes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 16:28:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/trees-with-holes/</guid><description>While working on a top-down synthesis prototype, I got distracted by the issue of how to represent incomplete program fragments, with holes to be filled in.
The simple way:
type expr = | One | Plus of expr * expr | Hole let (__) = Hole let hypothesis = Plus (__, __) and this would probably have worked, but with quadratic-time substitution, since all the holes would be at the bottom of the tree.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Z3's proofs</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/z3-proofs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 12:00:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/z3-proofs/</guid><description>A writeup of a presentation I gave in class.
SMT solvers like Z3 are often also called automated theorem provers. Why? What do their proofs look like?
An SMT solver tells us if a formula in first-order logic (augmented with various theories) is satisfiable1: there is some assignment of variables that makes the formula true. Z3 can even produce such an assignment.
from z3 import * i = Int(&amp;#39;i&amp;#39;) solve(i &amp;gt; 0) [i = 1] Not every formula is satisfiable, though.</description></item><item><title>Pretty stack-and-heap diagrams</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/stack-heap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:13:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/stack-heap/</guid><description>I'm teaching an introductory programming class this semester, which introduced students to the runtime stack and the heap in one of the early tutorials.
For consistency across face-to-face and online classes, I decided to have the diagrams in my slides instead of drawing them terribly over and over.
While there were lots of references for drawing such diagrams by hand, there didn't seem to be any small and simple tools for generating them.</description></item><item><title>Mouseover Minesweeper</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/mouseover-minesweeper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 20:03:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/mouseover-minesweeper/</guid><description>Automation in puzzle games is tricky to balance. The issue is that puzzle games often involve a lot of busywork, e.g. keeping track of the possibilities for each cell in Sudoku, and that removing the tedious parts allows the player to focus on the &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; parts of the puzzle.
Unfortunately, the parts of the game that are core to its experience can be quite subjective. Automation can also quickly spiral out of control, where adding a single rule (e.</description></item><item><title>Transparent iOS backups</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/ios-backups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 17:49:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/ios-backups/</guid><description>Backing up an iOS device is nice and simple: there's iCloud, or connecting your device, opening Finder, and clicking Back Up Now. Unfortunately this process is also rather opaque: all we can do in Finder is to create and restore backups, not view their contents. I'd like to be able to extract individual files and archive them elsewhere.
At the time of writing there are no up-to-date and polished open source apps for simply viewing backup data in an open format, so here we'll explore how iOS backups are structured and figure out how to extract the raw files.</description></item><item><title>SATB Bird</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/satb-bird/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 23:49:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/satb-bird/</guid><description>Flappy Bird and choral singing have a lot in common. Bird analogies, gestures, calls, and songs are common in warmups, and in both activities, you are trying to steer a small flapping thing along a fine line through (your) pipes, backed by a lush (musical) landscape.
To make that less of a reach, I cobbled together a prototype of a singing-powered Flappy Bird, based on an open source clone of the game.</description></item><item><title>Bags of puzzle pieces in ASP</title><link>https://dariusf.github.io/asp-puzzle-pieces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 12:15:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dariusf.github.io/asp-puzzle-pieces/</guid><description>Answer set programming is an offshoot of traditional logic programming with a number of nice properties: programs always terminate, are fully declarative (i.e. clause ordering doesn't matter and search is complete, unlike Prolog), and have a well-defined semantics. Modelling a domain with relations is a wonderfully high-level way to reason about things, allowing complex rules to be represented concisely.
ASP is typically applied to hard search problems, but can model pretty much anything.</description></item></channel></rss>